Yazid Musa

Frontend Developers

EXPERIENCE

Shopify Developer/ Chrome Extension Developer

Upworks

10/2021 - Present

- Development of shopify stores and themes for clients with frontend toolkits using JavaScript, Shopify CLI, HTML5, CSS3, Less, SaSS, Bootstrap, NPM
- Development of google chrome extensions for clients with frontend toolkits using JavaScript, google chrome APIs, HTML5, CSS3, Less, SaSS, Bootstrap, NPM

Software Developer

Voguepay

03/2020 - Present

- Involved in API request, response and design patterns for data management.
- · Development of SPA (Single Page Applications) Enterprise

Portals using with Frontend Toolkits

using React, Redux, ES5/6 and JavaScript.

- · Functional Testing of Web Applications.
- Worked in an Agile team and adhering to Agile Methodology practices such as Stand-ups / Logging time and Jira tickets.

WordPress Developer

04/2020 - 02/2021

- Design, implement and manage company website using WordPress
- · Manage front-end and back-end website development
- Maintain well-documented, reusable, and transferable code
- Create WordPress plug-ins and themes for customers
- · Create WordPress plug-ins and themes for customers
- · Integrated payment systems both local and international

Software Developer Intern

Eledgefund Institute Of Traders

08/2019 - 02/2020

 PHP Development and Debugging via XDebug to fix Customer applications errors I surpassed my average tickets for the

month

• Development of Modules/ Components to extend the

In-house Framework, this allowed extension

Framework for specific customers

Responsible for hardware and software repairs, installations and

configurations on staff computers.

- **** 07061889992
- musa.yazid49@gmail.com
- ★ https://musa-yazid.netlify.app/
- Lagos, Nigeria

SUMMARY

Musa Yazid is a Front-end Engineer with 2+ years of experience using Front-end and also familiar with Backend Technologies, I have experience with Agile Methodologies and Software Development Life cycle. I have good background with Core JavaScript and the DOM API. I have worked with several frameworks such as DojoToolkit, AngularJS, Angular, Vue, Svelte and React. I majorly use React due to my long background working for Enterprise companies.

SKILLS

Intermediate ReactJs ES5 & ES6 Intermediate JavaScript Intermediate **TypeScript** Beginner VueJs Intermediate **AWS** Beginner WordPress, Joomla, Shopify Intermediate Intermediate Linux Intermediate Node, ExpressJs

LANGUAGES

English Fluent

EDUCATION

Industrial Physics

University Of Benin

2016

Bachelor Of Science In Industrial Physics

Final Year Project

Developed a traffic control system running on micro-controllers with C Programming and Arduino rate by 70%.

• I moved from intern to full developer after completing 20 tickets within four months as opposed to 20 tickets in six months stipulated by the company. I was a full-time developer within a month of internship.

CERTIFICATES

Cloud Based(https://crio-assets.s3.apsouth-1.amazonaws.com/social/ d6d9b9d2661abd08/c98b3b739906d179.png) 05/2021 - Present